# Sidney A. Blum

# CFP®, CPA/PFS, ChFC

Sid Founded GreatLight Fee Only Advisors, LLC (GLFOA) in 2005. GLFOA is an affordable planning and investment alternative in the North Shore Chicago and Las Vegas areas. Sid was a co-founder of Successful Financial Solutions, Inc. in 1994, which merged with a large fee-only firm in 2003. Sid does financial planning with an emphasis on income and estate taxes, retirement planning, and investment planning. Sid's has significant background that includes, Education, Experience, Professional & Community Service, and Professional & Media Recognition.

## **EDUCATION**

- University of Illinois, degree in accounting
- CERTIFIED PUBLIC ACCOUNTANT (CPA) 1975
- CERTIFIED FINANCIAL PLANNER™ [CFP©] certification in 1987
- AICPA Certificate of Education Achievement in Personal Financial Planning in 1988
- Chartered Financial Consultant (ChFC) in 1989
- AICPA specialty designation of Personal Financial Specialist (CPA/PFS) in 1991

#### **EXPERIENCE**

- Practicing as a CPA since 1975
- Practicing as a financial advisor since 1987

## PROFESSIONAL & COMMUNITY SERVICE

- Adjunct Faculty of the College for Financial Planning
  - o Financial Planning Section of Roosevelt University in Chicago
  - Northwestern University College for Continuing Studies
- Adjunct Faculty of University of Illinois Chicago MBA Program Personal Financial Planning
- AICPA Resource Panel of the Center for Investment Advisory Services
- Illinois CPA Society
  - o Personal Financial Planning Committee
  - o Finance Committee
  - Consulting Services Executive Committee
  - Investment Services Task Force and Finance Committee
- Board Member Service Present and Past
  - Licensed Independent Network of CPA Financial Planners (LINC)
  - Association of CPA Financial Planners
    - o Greater Chicago International Association of Financial Planners (IAFP)
    - o North Shore Chapter IAFP (as past President and Chairman of the Board)
    - National Association of Personal Financial Advisors-Midwest Regional Board (NAPFA) as President 2002-2003
    - Chair of NAPFA Midwest and Member NAPFA National Board 2003-2004
    - NAPFA National Nominating Committee 2006
    - Chair of NAPFA National Conference 2006
    - o Illinois FPA Nominating Committee as V.P. of Corp. Sponsorship for FPA North Shore Council
    - Illinois FPA Advisory Board
    - o FPA Illinois Board of Directors 2005
    - o Rotary Club of Wilmette, Illinois

#### PROFESSIONAL & MEDIA RECOGNITION

- Worth's annual list of "The Best Financial Advisers" from 1996 to 2002
- Medical Economics as one of the 150 best financial advisers for doctors since 2000 to 2005
- Dental Practice Report Best Financial Advisers For Dentists 2012
- University of Illinois Business School Alumni Association Leadership Award in 2005
- Contributor to Beyond the 401(k), a book published by Investors Press

- Contributor to Everything Money, published by Adams Media Corporation
- Contributor to Easy Ways to Organize Your Taxes and Money by Publications International in 1999 and updated in 2006
- Contributor to Tips from the Top by Alpha
- Interviewed by several newsletters
  - Accounting Today
  - o AICPA Planner
  - o Dow Jones Investment Advisor
  - o Investment News
  - Moneysworth
- Answered financial and investment questions on several websites
  - o www.fundsinteractive.com
  - o www.quicken.com
  - o www.aol.com
  - o www.HowStuffWorks.com
- Contributed to articles
  - Chicago Sun-Times newspaper
  - o Chicago Tribune newspaper
  - o Money Magazine
  - Fortune Magazine
  - o Bloomberg
  - Smart Money
  - o Kiplinger Personal Finance
  - o Medical Economics
  - o North Shore Magazine
  - o Illinois CPA Society Insight Magazine
  - o numerous other publications
- Television appearances
  - o Nationally on Fox's Money program
  - locally on Financial Solutions (AT&T-public access)
  - Making Money (CLTV)
  - Accountability (WCIU- Stock Market Observer)
  - o Locally on ABC 7 Chicago
  - o Locally on Fox 32 Chicago
- Radio appearances
  - o Lee Ann Trotter's local radio show on US99
  - The Noon Business Hour on WBBM 780 AM with Sherman Kaplan & Kris Kridel
  - o WGN RADIO 720 AM Money Show with Bill Moller